MAKI HIROSE

Portfolio: makicoding.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/makihirose</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/makicoding</u> Contact: <u>maki@makicoding.com</u> | 347-615-1458 | New York, NY 11415

SUMMARY

UX/UI Designer with Full Stack Web Development skills, over ten years of visual experience in the Commercial Photography Industry and a Certified Scrum Master. Project leader for Advertising Photoshoots. Expert at color, composition and paying close attention to detail. Bilingual in English and Japanese.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

UX/UI: Project Management, Market Research, User Research, Contextual Inquiry, User Interviewing, Affinity Mapping, User Persona, Card Sorting, Information Architecture, User Flow, Sketching, Wireframing, Wireflow, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Heuristic Evaluation, Prototyping, Responsive Web Design.

Web Development: React, JavaScript, CSS, JSX, HTML5, Bootstrap, jQuery, RESTful API, AJAX, AXIOS, JSON, Firebase, Node, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, ORM, Handlebars, Heroku, JawsDB, mLab, Chrome DevTools, Git, GitHub, Agile, Scrum.

<u>Software:</u> Visual Studio Code, InVision, Sketch, Figma, XD, Photoshop, Lightroom, Bridge, After Effects, Premiere, Audition, Capture One, Photo Mechanic, Final Cut Pro, Logic Pro, Pro Tools, Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Google Slides, Command Line.

UX/UI PROJECTS

New Additions For Slack Mobile

Proposal: makicoding.github.io/portfolio/v001/010/assets/slides/SlackUXProposalV5.pdf

A proposal to integrate new features into Slack's existing mobile app, targeting adult students.

DiaBeatlt App

Proposal: makicoding.github.io/portfolio/v001/010/assets/slides/DiaBeatltUXProposalV4.pdf

App: diabeatit-9.herokuapp.com/

An app to help prevent diabetes through healthy eating.

Technologies used: React, JavaScript, CSS, Moment, Node, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, API and more.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

WeatherTastic App

App: makicoding.github.io/The-Weather-Appropriate-Clothing-App-MHLogic/index.html

An app that gives a recommendation of what to wear and pack based on the weather.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, API, JSON, AJAX, Daterangepicker, Moment.

The Barbershop App

App: evening-everglades-28431.herokuapp.com/index.html

A reservation app using a MySQL database hosted by JawsDB and deployed on Heroku.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Node, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, API and more.

MAKI HIROSE

Page Two of Two

EXPERIENCE

<u>UX/UI Designer & Web Developer</u> - Freelance - New York, NY

2019-Present

Conducted user research, reported insights to the team, discussed and ideated app designs using Sketch, performed usability testing using InVision and iterated designs. Solicited feedback from client. Coded app using React, vanilla JavaScript, MongoDB, MySQL and various other technologies. Prepared Google Slides presentation and demonstrated app to client.

Notable Clients: United Nations Tax Preparation Specialists.

Advertising Photographer & Owner - MAKIDIGITAL LLC - New York, NY

2012-Present

Founded and operated business, including key decision-making for B2B and B2C marketing, social media, photography and video shoots. Headed teams on large scale Advertising Photoshoots, shooting images for both web apps and print, working alongside Directors of Ideation and Brand Managers. Executed photography/videography, photo retouching and video editing. Directed day-to-day operations including project management, client meetings, pitching, estimating, bidding, price negotiation and bookkeeping.

Notable Clients: L'Oréal, Maybelline, Diageo, Smirnoff, Tanqueray Gin, IW Harper, JUICE Pharma,
Sterling Vineyards, Landor, Colangelo, Grind Espresso Spirit, Califresca, Blade & Bow, JWT and more.

<u>Digital Imaging Specialist & Front End Developer</u> - *Drive In Studios DI24* - New York, NY 2007-2012 Supervised and facilitated all digital imaging, photo retouching and digital asset management on Advertising Photoshoots. Designed, developed, coded using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Flash, updated, troubleshooted and maintained company and various clients' websites.

• **Notable Clients:** IBM, GE, Citibank, Microsoft, Sony, Vodafone, Merck & Co., Allianz, AstraZeneca, Ikea, Adidas Y-3, Kate Spade, Absolut Vodka, Six Flags, Macy's, Gillette, Food Network and more.

EDUCATION

New York University - New York, NY

2019-Present

UX Design for Emerging Technologies

General Assembly - New York, NY

2019

UX Design

Columbia University - New York, NY

2019

Full Stack Web Development

New York University - New York, NY

Bachelors of Fine Art in Photography & Imaging - *Tisch School of the Arts* New York University Honors Scholar and Founders' Day Award Recipient

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) - Scrum Alliance - New York, NY

2019